Daniel Bonasser

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/daniel-bonasser/

Github: github.com/danvb112

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: Javascript / Typescript / HTML / CSS / SASS

• Stack: React / NextJs / React Flow / React Redux / React Native / Tailwind / Styled Components

• Tests: Unit / Integration / E2E / Jest / Playwright

• Methodologies: Agile / Scrum / Kanban

Profile

Software engineer with experience in developing, maintaining and testing frontends behind no-code applications, marketplaces, that serve diverse companies and users on a daily basis. I have worked on product teams using agile methodologies and developing several new features, new projects, technical debts and bug fixes. I have successfully delivered high-quality solutions for highly used web applications. Throughout my career, I've found joy in problem-solving and helping people. I always strive to express my viewpoints thoughtfully, while carefully considering the trade-offs of different technology choices. Also, I like to take part in healthy discussions regarding the best technical solution based on the project's needs.

EXPERIENCE

Liferay
Software Engineer

Pernambuco - BR

Jul 2023 - Present

Email: danielbonasser@gmail.com

Mobile: +55-81-998291996

- Increased Liferay Objects management time by 45%: By developing the Model Builder, using React and React Flow.
- Implemented 35+ new features for Liferay Objects frontend: By using React.
- Increased performance by 82% when loading repeatable form fields: By rewriting code and eliminating unnecessary loop iterations.
- o Decreased the number of data loss bugs by 90%: By converting the code from JSP to React.
- \circ Reduced the number of unnecessary re-renders by 50%: Improving the user experience when converting code from JSP to React.
- **Designed and built 20 frontend pages**: By using React, while developing and implementing the initial architecture of Liferay Marketplace.
- Mentored more than 30 new interns at the company: Teaching them about React and its ecosystem and how it was applied to the Liferay Portal.

Junior Software Engineer

Jan 2022 - Jul 2023

- Improved user experience by 15%: By developing the Liferay Notification Templates frontend, using React
- o Delivered over 29 new features for Liferay Objects.: Successfully delivering the low-code milestone.
- Lowered the number of data loss bugs by 90%: By converting the code from JSP to React.
- \circ Decreased the number of unnecessary re-renders by 50%: Improving the user experience when converting code from JSP to React.
- Mentored more than 30 new interns at the company: Teaching them about React and its ecosystem and how it was applied to the Liferay Portal.

Software Engineer Intern

Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

- o Fixed around 40 bugs in Java and React: For Liferay Forms and Data Engine, enhancing system stability.
- o Developed the boolean field for Liferay Forms: Allowing users to incorporate this new field type in their forms.
- o Developed the Numeric Input mask: Enabling users to apply specific masks to their numeric fields

PROJECTS

- DevTips plataform: A platform where developers can register to mentor other developers for a fee. This project was developed at the university using React, Node.js, and React Native. Project: https://github.com/danvb112/DevTips
- Happy: a platform developed to register orphanages, and find them easily using the Leaflet library for maps and also Typescript, ReactJS and React Router Dom. You can check the project here: https://github.com/danvb112/happy
- NLW E-sports Project: An application developed to register and list details about games that can be used in E-sports. Application was made using NodeJs, ReactJs and React Native. Project Web: https://github.com/danvb112/nlw-eSports-Web Project mobile: https://github.com/danvb112/nlw-eSports-Mobile and Project server: https://github.com/danvb112/nlw-eSports-Server

EDUCATION

Estácio University of Pernambuco

Analysis and systems development, Technologist Degree

Pernambuco, Brazil Jan 2022 - Dec 2023

Rural Federal University of Pernambuco
Information Systems, Bachelor's Degree

Pernambuco, Brazil Jan 2019 - Jan 2022

Talks

• React for beginners, a talk with new Liferay interns about how React works and how to use it (Liferay) - May, 2023